John Ojo

Software Engineer



Pretoria, South Africa

Phone (Mobile): +27 82 485 3932 Email: johnoio97@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-ojo-b2b24115b/

Projects Portfolio:

https://iohnoio.github.io/Portfolio/#/

Education

Masters of Computing in Computer System Engineering Tshwane University of Technology 2022 - Present

BSc Honours Computer Science University of Pretoria 2019 - 2021

BSc IT University of Pretoria 2015 -2019

_

Certifications

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

SOFT SKILLS

Open to new ideas and opportunities.

Ability to work under pressure & multitask with ease.

Excellent communication & presentation skills.

PROFILE

What I love the most about my field is that it's all about solving problems, challenging each other as a team, enhancing user experience and continuously improving. I want to be part of a team that thinks differently and has various approaches to problem-solving while adding value to people. I want to be a bridge between customers and their solutions, and I want to build software that inspires and makes an impact.

WORK EXPERIENCE

BMW / Software Engineer

April 2023 - PRESENT

Integral member of the BMW parts and logistic services development & management team, ensuring software quality and agile practices. Job role responsibilities include:

- Drive frontend development, reviewing UX/UI designs & collaborating with Product Managers, Designers, & Business Analysts to determine user needs & business objectives.
- Ownership of service features & system applications, UI, & architecture design, scoping & development (project management) as well as unit, & integration testing & security reviewing.
- Created and optimised CI/CD pipelines for application deployment, automated testing, & vulnerability checks.
- Mentor developers to ensure delivery of frontend & backend tasks to build scalable and robust applications.

Retro Rabbit / Software Developer

January 2020 - March 2023

Technical Team Lead and Full-Stack Software Developer on various custom and innovative projects, ensuring coding standards & end-to-end project delivery. Job role responsibilities include:

- Led grad program of 32 graduates to deliver a booking and claim application to improve business claims accounting.
- Designed solution architecture, set up the cloud

Team player with ability to embrace leadership responsibility and roles.

Experienced in client & stakeholder interactions.

Determined to deliver on all client expectations.

_

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Software and Web development Solutions Architecture System Design DevOps Cloud Solutions Automated Testing

_

TECHNOLOGICAL COMPETENCIES

Programming languages:

 Java, Typescript, Javascript, C#, CSS, SCSS, HTML, YAML

Frameworks, Packaging & Platforms:

- Angular, React, NodeJs, ExpressJs, Quarkus, .NET Core
- Rancher, ArgoCD, GitHub Actions (CI/CD), Helm Charts, Terraform
- PostgreSQL, Redis, Microsoft SQL Server, MongoDB
- RabbitMQ, Kafka

Technologies & Areas:

- AWS & Azure Cloud Services with certifications
- Containerization incl. Docker, Kubernetes
- Databasing incl. MySql, NoSql

- environment, deployments, mentored graduates, scoped out project features, effort estimations, & code quality reviews.
- Delivered software solutions for various clients in the Medical, Risk Advisory, Insurance, Bookings and Claims domains from planning & development to testing & maintenance.

FAVOURITE PROJECTS

Bookings and Claims Project

- Description: An office and events bookings web application, as well as a claims web application.
- Role: Technical Team Lead, Managed 32 graduates, Full-stack developer.
- Tasks: Drew up solution architecture, set up the cloud environment, deployments, set up server, mentored graduates, managed team, scoped out project features, effort estimations, & reviewed pull requests.

Designer's Portfolio

- Description: Web application of a designer's portfolio to showcase their designs and experience
- Role: Fullstack developer.
- Tasks: Set up the cloud environment, set up CI/CD pipelines, developed fronted, developed backend, mobile responsiveness, & set up an email server
- Link to website: https://alfonzo28.github.io/ARL/#/

Other Projects:

Here is a link to other projects I have worked on: https://johnojo.github.io/Portfolio/#/